Isidro Servin

FullStack Software Engineer

- ism210296@gmail.com
- +1-236-514-0350
- linkedin.com/in/isidro-servín-5797a2176

About me

Highly motivated and experienced full-stack web developer with approximately 4 years of experience in developing, maintaining, and updating web applications. Strong skills in front-end development using ReactJS and VueJS frameworks, and back-end development with Express/NodeJS and Django/Python. Proficient in modern web development technologies such as JavaScript, CSS, jQuery, HTML5, and Bootstrap. Familiar with database management in SQL Server, MariaDB, PostgreSQL, and MongoDB.

Work Experience



Software Engineer.

Think Future Technologies.

May 2023 - Present (8 months).

TFT supplements its services with self-developed libraries/solutions/frameworks in the areas of Software Development, Testing, DevOps, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Blockchain and IoT.

Activities:

- Development of clean, testable and maintainable code in languages such as JavaScript, NodeJS, ReactJS, TypeScript, VueJS, Python.
- Together with my team, we have developed, maintained, and tested several web applications for clients.
- I collaborated in the backend creation of an application for a school using Nodejs with Express and TypeScript as development tools.



Full-Stack Web Developer.

Apocalipsis Automation.

January 2020 - May 2023(3 years, 4 months).

Apocalipsis Automation is a company dedicated to providing a wide expert response to any industrial need in the area of automation and control.

Activities:

- Developed and maintained web applications for the company's clients in the automation and control industry.
- Utilized VueJS and ReactJS frameworks for front-end development and Express/NodeJS for back-end development.
- Implemented modern web development technologies such as JavaScript, CSS, JQuery, HTML5, Bootstrap, Graphql, Axios and Jest.
- Improved web application performance by optimizing code and implementing best practices.



Web Developer

Legalex GS.

April 2021 - December 2021 (8 months).

Legalex is a Certification Services Provider (PSC) accredited by the Ministry of Economy to provide the services of Issuance of Certificates of Conservation of Data Messages in accordance with NOM-151-SCFI-2016 and Digital Time Stamps (Timestamp).

Performed activities:

- Developed, maintained and updated existing components in commercial products.
- Utilized Java, JS, CSS, JQuery, Java Servlets, JSP, HTML5, AJAX for back-end and front-end web development.
- Implemented PostgreSQL v13 as the database management system.
- Utilized Bitbucket for version control.



Web and Android Developer (Internship) Ecovive.

June 2019 - December 2019 (6 months)

- Developed a web application to control the inventory of the construction company using CodeIgniter framework, Bootstrap v4 and GoogleCharts.
- Developed an Android application similar to UberEats that allowed the company's restaurant to make home deliveries, using Android Studio, Kotlin and FireBase as a NoSQL real-time database.

Education History



Software Development Diploma Institution: Red Deer Polytechnic. Year of Graduation: March 2024



Bachelor's Degree in Computer Systems Engineering.

Institution: Technological Institute of Morelia.

Year of Graduation: 2019

Languajes

80 % 70 %

Git Repository



https://github.com/isidroServin

Relevant Skills

- Front-end Development: ReactJS, VueJS, JavaScript, CSS, JQuery, HTML5, Bootstrap, ApexCharts, Jest, TypeScript.
- Back-end Development: Express/NodeJS, Java, Java Servlets, JSP.
- Database Management: SQLServer, mongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- Version Control: GIT, Bitbucket.
- Containerization: Docker.
- AWS.

